

Plön, Germany

I am a Computer Scientist with 8+ years of experience working as a programmer and R&D researcher in state-of-art projects relating to Computer Graphics, Computer Vision and AI. This taught me how to be a quick learner, adaptable and self-driven. I am passionate trying out new solutions to problems and working in a team of curious people. My main interests nowadays are Computer Graphics (mainly rendering) and Simulations.

Personal Projects & Skills

(links on project titles)

Vulkan Renderer

A Generic Renderering Library I wrote using C++ and Vulkan. Currently, it supports both forward and deferred

rendering styles, custom shaders and custom rendergraphs for post-processing and other effects. I am still adding features and implementing modern algorithms as i work on it.

Personal Website

my contact info and links to my personal projects and experiments. I built it using Javascript (Three.js)

Languages

Portuguese (native speaker), English (C1), German (B1)

Experience

Freelance Brazil -> Plön, Germany

• Relocation to Germany. (approx. 1 months)

• German Studies. Acquired B1 Certificate. (approx. 7 months)

- Tutoring Computer Graphics, Programming and Machine Learning. (approx. 2 year)
- Studied CG on Web platforms (Javascript, Threejs) (approx. 1 year)
- Studied Vulkan and modern Graphics APIs. (ongoing, approx 1.5 years.)
- Wrote my own Vulkan based Rendering Library. (ongoing, approx 1 year.)

Lenscope Remote, (São Paulo. Brazil)

COMPUTER VISION/GRAPHICS SPECIALIST

Jul 2021 - Nov 2021

Nov 2021

- R&D of Computer Vision and Graphics algorithms applied to the optometry business.
- · Worked directly with a PhD teammate, embedded into a larger AGILE team of 7 developers and 2 managers.
- · Project in Python with Keras, Pandas and Numpy.

Virtual Humans Lab (PUCRS)

RESEARCHER

Porto Alegre, Brazil

Nov 2017 - Mar 2021

- Created BioClouds, a large crowd simulation model. Resulted in 5 published papers. Made in C# using Unity3D.
- Modeled disaster situations coupling Fluid Simulation and Crowd Simulation. Integrated Fluid Simulations written in C++, with a Unity3D based Crowd Simulation written in C#.
- · Created Computer Vision tools, to analyze street camera footage, written in Python using OpenCV.

HP inc. / PUCRS Porto Alegre, Brazil R&D INTERNSHIP May 2016 - Oct 2017

- Started in an AGILE team of 3 interns and 1 technical lead. Built a tool in Python to label video datasets.
- Migrated to an AGILE team of 6 members, composed of 4 interns, 1 machine learning specialist, and 1 manager.
- · Implemented the Computer Vision system that integrated a video camera with gesture commands
- Both projects in C++ with OpenCV, Java and Python.

NLP Lab (PUCRS) Porto Alegre, Brazil

RESEARCH INTERNSHIP

Aug 2015 - Apr 2016

- Participated in publishing SUMMIT++, an annotated corpus for the Portuguese language.
- Work in a team for 2 interns, 3 PhD candidates. Project in Java and Python.

Degrees

MSc, Computer Science

Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

Mar 2019 - Mar 2021

· Awarded a full ride merit scholarship.

BSc, Computer Science

Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

PONTIFICAL CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF RIO GRANDE DO SUL (PUCRS)

PONTIFICAL CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF RIO GRANDE DO SUL (PUCRS)

Dec 2018